Guide to the Records of the NYU Abu Dhabi Institute AD.RG.024.1
NYU Abu Dhabi, Archives and Special Collections
- Audiovisual Event Files (Conferences and Programs), 2007-2015
  - AY 2012-2013
    - The Paradox of Classical Music, May 9, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Judit Frigyesi
    - An Evening of Song and Poetry, May 11, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Celina Charlier, Marcio Miele
    - Pre-Oil Economy in the UAE: The Work-a-Day World Before Oil, May 13, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Philip Kennedy, James Toth, Hassan Al Naboodah, John Wilkinson, Derek Kennet, Frauke Heard-Bey, Awam Amkpa, Fatma Al-Sayegh, Aqil Kazim, Daniel Potts, Ismail Hakki Genc, Fahad Bishara, Ronald Hawker, Pia Anderson, Jayanti Robin Maitra, El-Sayed El-Aswad, David Heard
    - Globalizing Histories of Science, Technology, and Medicine, May 19-21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Lauren Minsky, Hugh Slotten, Justin Stearns
    - Modern Islam and Science, May 19, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: H.E. Ekmeleddin hsanolu
    - The Power of Theory: From Physics to Neuroscience, May 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: David Hansel
  - AY 2013-2014
    - Trade, History, and Network in the Indian Ocean, Sept. 4, 2013 (Box E-records)
    - We are all Corals Now, Sep. 30, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Margaret Wertheim
    - The Life We Live and The Art We Make, Oct. 08, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sue Coe; Zena el Khalil; Joanne Savio
    - The Marvelous, Mundane Orient of Abu Zayd and Ibn Battutah, Oct. 10, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tim Mackintosh-Smith
    - The Waterpipe: A Cultural Past Time or a Public Health Threat?, Oct. 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Wasim Maziak
    - Waterpipe Tobacco smoking, Oct. 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Kenneth Ward
    - First International Conference on Waterpipe Tobacco Smoking, Oct. 22. 2013 (Box E-records)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Unreadable USB drive
    - Health Inequities in the Arab Region: A Call for Public Policy Reforms, Oct. 23, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Hoda Rashad, Paula England
    - Dark Matter: Evidence, Experiments, and Properties, Oct. 24, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Hogg
    - 1967 and 2011: Arab Intellectual Responses, Oct. 29, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Elizabeth Kassab
    - Why is the UAE a Federation?, Oct. 29, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Frauke Heard-Bey
    - Exploring Islamic Art at the Met: A Walking Guide, Nov. 07, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Navina Najat Haidar
    - CLEAR WATERS: Flute and Piano Recital, Nov. 09, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Celina Charlier; Edmundo Villani-Crtes
    - Understanding Nabati Poetry: Tools of the Trade, Nov. 11, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Saad Abdullah Sowayan; Marcel Kurpershoek
    - Abu Dhabi Reads: The American Granddaughter, Nov. 14, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Joanne Bui; Salwa Mikdadi; Cyrus Patel; Deborah Williams
    - Climate Change: A Failure of Politics?, Nov. 17, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Steven; John Ashton
    - Beiruti Theater in Action, Nov. 19, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Catherine Coray; Mona Knio; Maya Zbib; Hanane Hajj Ali; Lina Abyad; Amahl Khouri
    - TURNAROUND: Third World Lessons for First World Growth, Nov. 21, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jason Beckerman; Peter Blair Henry
    - Young Voices of Abu Dhabi: Plan 2030, Nov. 23, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Nils Lewis; Sila Abu Dhabi
    - Impossible Citizens: Dubai's Indian Diaspora, Nov. 26, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Justin Stearns; Neha Vora
    - Arabic Philosophy within/without the Western Canon, Dec. 04, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Matthew Silverstein; Taneli Kukkonen
    - Fifty Years with Mandela: From Lawbreaker to Lawmaker, Dec. 08, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Judith Miller; Albie Sachs
    - Sheikh Zayed bin Sultan Al Nahyan, Falcons, and Abbasid Hunting Poetry, Dec.10, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Montgomery
    - Muslim World or Ummah? Origins, Content, and Evolution of Pan-Islamic Thought, Dec. 16, 2013 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cemil Aydin
    - Humanitarian and Development Aid for the World's Children: Perspectives from the UAE, Jan. 08, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tariq Al Gurg, Beau Crowder, Lara Hussein, Maysa Jalbout, Joan Lombardi, J. Lawrence Aber
    - Transforming Settings for Children and Youth: Towards a Global Science and Practice, Jan. 08-09, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: J. Lawrence Aber
    - Doubt in Islamic Law: Burden or Benefit?, Jan. 12, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Intisar A. Rabb
    - Scheherazade's Children, Jan. 14, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Marina Warner, Paulo Horta, Philip Kennedy
    - Life on the Baynunah River: Abu Dhabi 7 Million Years Ago, Jan. 16, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Faysal Bibi
    - Understanding Ethics, Jan. 19, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Matthew Silverstein
    - Leadership Across Boundaries, Jan. 25, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Kate Otto, Noura Alturki, Butheina Kazim, David Moinina Sengeh
    - Forming Intersections and Dialogues (FIND): The Artist and the Scholar, Jan. 28, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Yasser Elsheshtawy, Roberto Lopardo
    - Of Gases, Prices, Triangles and Men, Jan. 30, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cedric Villani
    - The Transformation of Civil Wars, 1800-2010, Feb. 02, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Stathis Kalyvas
    - Encouraging Innovation: How to Accelerate the Discovery of New Medicines, Feb. 03, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mark Murcko
    - In the Land of the Ichthyophagi: The Archaeology of Abu Dhabi's Coast and Islands, Feb. 05, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mark Beech
    - Technics and Politics of Urban Expertise: A Gulf Case Study, Feb. 09, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ahmad Kanna
    - The Enlightenment in Global History, Feb. 12, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sebastian Conrad
    - The UAE in Early Islamic History, Feb. 13, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Timothy Power
    - Building Apps for the Social Good in the Arab World, Feb. 16, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Autism: New Mutations, Genes, and Pathways, Feb. 18, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Evan E. Eichler
    - Genomics & Systems Biology IV, Feb. 19-20, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Claude Desplan, Michael Purugganan, Richard Bonneau, Kristin Gunsalus, Fabio Piano, Kourosh Salehi-Ashtiani
    - Whispers of Abu Dhabi History in the Oral Tradition, Feb. 20, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Khaled Salem Sultan AlDhaheri
    - Tales That Travel: Storytelling in Eurasia, Feb. 24-25, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Maurice Pomerantz, Evelyn Birge Vitz
    - Metamorphoses, Lovers, Heroic Deeds, Feb. 25, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Anne Azema, Shira Kammen, Mehmet Ali Sanlikol
    - Center for Technology and Economic Development IV, Feb. 25, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Neither Visionaries nor Bean Counters: Solving the Dilemma of Company Creation, Mar. 04, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Merrick Furst, Matt Chanoff
    - Girl Rising: Storytelling for Social Change, Mar. 06, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Khuloud Al Nuwais, Nicole Lopez Del Carrill, Tom Yellin, Maysa Jalbout
    - Dark Matter: The Mystery Deepens, Mar. 11, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Translation Today: A Muslim Suicide, Mar. 13, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: BenSalem Himmich, Roger Allen
    - The Art of Diplomacy in the 21st Century: Contemporary Challenges to an Ancient Profession, Mar. 16, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ambassador Francois Barras
    - Navigating Deterrence, Mar. 19, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Samuel Rascoff, Zachary Goldman
    - Exploring Nowhere: Digital Maps, and the Historical Problem of Location, Mar. 30, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Carolyn Dinshaw, Marget Long
    - How Migration Makes Meaning: Slavery and Abolition in the Atlantic and Indian Oceans, Mar. 31-Apr. 2, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Awam Ampka, Gunja SenGupta
    - Oceans in Literary Imagination and Historical Consciousness, Apr. 01, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sugata Bose, Caryl Phillips, Awam Ampka, Gunja SenGupta
    - Consciousness: How the Brain Creates the Mind, Apr. 06, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sid Koulder
    - Putting Global Intellectual History in its Place, Apr. 14, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Janaki Bakhle
    - Nabati Poetry: An Introduction and Recitation, Apr. 16, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mohamed Alhashimi
    - Heart or Head? How Brain Science Alters Our Understanding of Emotions and Decisions, Apr. 20, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Liz Phelps
    - Noise from the Middle East: A Micro-Festival of Electronic Music, Apr. 24, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Carlos Guedes, Neil van der Linden, Hasan Hujairi, Mazen Kerbaj, Karim Sultan
    - Arabic Fiction Now: A Conversation with the International Prize for Arabic Fiction (IPAF) Shortlist, Apr. 27, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Wail Hassan, Youssef Fadel, Inaam Kachachi, Khaled Khalifa, Abdelrahim Lahbibi, Ahmed Mourad, Ahmed Saadawi
    - Islam and Christendom: Pope Pius II and the Entanglement of Civilizations, Apr. 28, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Christopher Ocker
    - Fine Art -- Why Care? Saving a Van Gogh, May 1, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Cornelia Peres
    - Saving Fine Arts [at Manarat Al Saadiyat], May 01, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Tempest in the Sun, May 05, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Abu Dhabi in Photographs: The Birth of a City, May 08, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Langton
    - Transnational Cinema/Media Studies, May 11-13, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ella Shohat, Robert Stam
    - The Cinema, the Middle East, and the Transnational, May 11, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ella Shohat, Robert Stam, Talal Al-Muhanna, Rasha Salti, Richard Pea, Viola Shafik
    - Good Science, Bad Science, and the Shroud of Turin, May 14, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Joel Bernstein
  - AY 2014-2015
    - The Decline and Fall of the Safavid Empire, Sept. 14, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Rudi Matthee
    - The Islamic World in the 18th Century: Before Colonialism, Sept. 14,-15 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Sajjad Rizvi, Justin Stearns
    - Commodities, Culture, and Maritime Technology: Connecting the Indian Ocean World, Sept. 17, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Himanshu Prabha Ray
    - Lines and Flows: The Beginning and End of Borders, Sept. 24, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Alan Bersin
    - Radical Craft: Re-imagining Crochet, Sep. 29, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Toshiko Horiuchi MacAdam, Shauna Richardson, Christine Wertheim, Jill Magi
    - Reefs, Rubbish, and Reason, Oct. 1, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: John Burt, Margaret Wertheim, Lawrence Weschler, Alexis Gambis
    - Musical Diversity in Concert II, Oct. 12, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Gideon Alorwoyle, Akshay Anantapadmanabhan, Grard Assayag, Jaime Oliver, Barak Schmool
    - Cross-disciplinary and Multi-cultural Perspectives on Musical Rhythm II, Oct. 12-15, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Juan Bello, Carlos Guedes, Robert Rowe, Godfried Toussaint
    - The Single-Handed Molecules of Life, Oct. 15, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: James Canary
    - Anachronisms and Retrojections: Sunni--Shi'i Relations in Context, Oct. 22, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Tariq al-Jamil
    - The Neuroscience of Memory, Oct. 27, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Charles Gross
    - Rising Coastal Seas on a Warming Earth, Oct. 27-29, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Denise Holland, David M. Holland
    - Arabic Theater in Translation: Language, Culture, and Politics, Oct. 30, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Hassan Abdulrazzak, Abdullah Alkafri, Robert Myers, Nada Saab, Catherine Coray
    - The Legitimation of Autocracy in the Ancient World, Nov. 02-03, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - Where is "World Literature"?, Nov. 04, 2014 (Box E-records)
    - [ISEA2014 Program at NYU Abu Dhabi Panel Discussion], Nov. 06, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Carlos Guedes, Scott Fitzgerald
    - The Legacy of the Cairo Genizah, Nov. 09, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Judy Miller, Philip Kennedy, Mark Cohen, Amitav Ghosh
    - Global Citizenship Commission, Nov. 09, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Gordon Brown, John Sexton (audio only)
    - Plagues: From Bubonic to Ebola, Nov. 12, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Daniel Malamud
    - A Parable of Islam and the West: Margaret Marcus and Mawlana Mawdudi, Nov. 17, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Deborah Baker
    - NYU Abu Dhabi SILA Conference, Nov. 22, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Myung-In Sohn, Alf Lim
    - Engineering the Future: Building with Biology, Nov. 25, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Pamela Silver
    - Toward a Theory of Everything in the World of Human Behavior, Nov. 27, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Guillermina Jasso Silver
    - An Ottoman History of World War I, Nov. 30, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mustafa Aksakal
    - Modern Architecture in Abu Dhabi, 1968-1992 [FIND], Dec. 07, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mo Ogrodnik, Pascal Menoret, Yasser Eisheshtawy, Sherina Al Sowaidi
    - Reversible: Narrating Identity from the Inside Out and Outside In, Dec. 7-9, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mo Ogrodnik
    - Comparative Political Development in Post-Soviet Eurasia and the Middle East, Dec. 08, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Georgi Derlugulan, Henry Hale
    - The Beginnings of Shi'i Identity: Ritual and Sacred Space in Early Islam, Dec. 10, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Justin Stearns, Najam Haider
    - Exhibits Without Borders: Museum Professions in a Global World, Dec. 14, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Salwa Mikdadi, Leigh Markopoulos, Moaza Matar, Marjorie Schwarzer, Glenn Wharton
    - From Antarah to Faris Shidyaq: The Art of Editing in Translation [Emirates Writers Union], Dec. 15, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Ma'an Al Tai, Philip Kennedy, Tahera Qutbuddin, Devin Stewart
    - The Unpredictable Past: National Museums and Stable Civil Societies, Dec. 15-16, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Robert Parthesius
    - National Museums: Peace Brokers or Peace Breakers? An Afghan Case Study, Dec. 16, 2014 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Susanne Annen, Brendan Cassar, Omara Khan Massoudi, Robert Parthesius, Omar Sultan
    - Is Capitalism Moral? Tales Old and New, Jan. 8, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Jonathan Haidt
    - Supporting Women's Work in the UAE: Transitions, Trajectories and Intersections, Jan. 11, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: May Al-Dabbagh, Fatima Al-Shamsi, Anisa Al-Sharif, Rabea Ataya
    - Safety and Security: The Basis for Stable Development, Jan. 12, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: His Excellency Ranko Krivokapic
    - Battling Cancer with Particle Physics: The Evolution of Hadron Therapy, Jan. 15, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Fernando Ferroni
    - Cultures of Conviction, Jan. 18, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Katia Vavova
    - Dr. Jane Goodall: Reasons for Hope, Jan. 20, 2015 (Box E-records)
    - Satire in the Muslim World: Molla Nasreddin, Jan. 27, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Slavs and Tatars Art Collective
    - The Rise and Decline of the American Presidency, Feb. 01, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Jeremi Suri
    - Ibadi Islam: Its Origins and Place in Islamic Thought, Feb. 08, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Valerie J. Hoffman
    - Family Matters: Theorizing State and Family in the Arab Region, Feb. 10, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Suad Joseph
    - Art As Diplomacy: UAE/USA Talk and Concert, Feb. 12, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Bryan Waterman, Noor Al Suwaidi, Mary McBride
    - Coral Reefs of Arabia: Exploring New Insights and Opportunities on Our Regional Reefs, Feb. 15-17, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: John A. Burt
    - How Cells Export Proteins and Small RNAs, Feb. 17, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Randy Schekman
    - Genomics and Systems Biology V, Feb. 17-19, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Justin Blau, Claude Desplain, Kristin Gunsalus, Michael Purugganan, Kourosh Salehi-Ashtiani
    - Imagine Science Abu Dhabi: Where Science Meets Art and Becomes Culture [Film Festival], Feb. 19-21, 2015 (Box E-records)
    - Islam and the Choice of Liberalism, Feb. 23, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Joseph Massad
    - Problems of Peace-Making: Getting Russia to Talk about Ukraine, Feb. 25, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Speakers/Officiators: James Traub, Martin Griffiths
    - Music of the Arabian Peninsula, Mar. 01-03, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Speakers/Officiators: Virginia Danielson, Walter Feldman, Andy Eisenberg
    - Kuwaiti Heritage: The Mayouf Bahri Band (performance), Mar. 02, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Speakers/Officiators: The Mayouf Bahri Band, Walter Feldman, Ghazi Al-Mulaifi
    - An Evening of Nabati Poetry (performance), Mar. 04, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Progam Officiators/Speakers: Mohamed Alhashimi, Ebraheem Al Khalidi
    - Nabati Poetry in the 21st Century: The History and Development of its Genres, Mar. 04-05, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Philip Kennedy, Marcel Kurpershoek
    - Photography's Shifting Terrain: Emerging Histories and New Practices, Mar. 08-10, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Issam Nassar, Shamoon Zamir
    - Gathering Photographs, Shaping Collective Memory, Mar. 8, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Susan Melselas, Shelley Rice
    - The UN Security Council in an Era of Great-Power Rivalry, Mar. 09, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: David Malone, James Traub
    - Cosmopolitan Currents in the Indian Ocean, Mar. 15-17, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officators/Speakers: Akbar Keshodkar, Lauren Minsky
    - Entering the Tiger's Mouth: Indian Sepoys in the First Opium War, Mar. 16, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Amitav Ghosh
    - A Paradox of Plenty? Energy Insecurity in the UAE, Mar. 18, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Li-Chen Sim
    - Objectivity: How Much Can We Have?, Mar. 29, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Gordon Belot
    - From Rags to Riches: A Story of Abu Dhabi, Mar. 31, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Mohammed Al Fahim
    - Creating FREEJ: The Evolution of Lammtara Studio, Apr. 06, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Mohammed Saeed Harib
    - Betraying Empathy: Moral Trauma and Our Capacity to Care, Apr. 09, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Carol Gilligan
    - Angel Rising Investor Education Symposium, Apr. 11, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Ramesh Jagannathan
    - Hackathon: Building Apps for Social Good in the Arab World, Apr. 12, 2015 (Box E-records)
    - Connected Through Heritage: Developing Regional Networks for Heritage and Museum Studies, Apr. 13-14, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Robert Parthesius
    - View From Inside: Contemporary Arab Artists in Conversation, Apr. 15, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Tarek Al Ghoussein, Shamoon Zamir
    - Shakespeare as Global Cultural Heritage, Apr. 18-19, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Cyrus R.K. Patell, Ruben Polendo, Katherine Williams
    - The Evolution of Emirati Dress, Apr. 21, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Reem Elmutwalli
    - Is The Earth Rare?, Apr. 23, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: James Kasting
    - A New Approach in Psychotherapy "ACT": Acceptance and Commitment Therapy, Apr. 26, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speaker: Louise McHugh
    - New Kinds of War Demand New Kinds of Peacemaking, Apr. 28, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: David Harland, James Traub
    - Arabic Fiction Now, May 04, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speakers: Jana Elhassan, Lina Hawyan Elhassan, Ahmed el-Madini, Shukri Mabkhout, Atef Abu Saif, Hammour Ziada, Marilyn Booth
    - Hunting the Sand Tiger: Abu Dhabi and the Quest for Oil 1953-1958, May 07, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speaker: James Langton
    - The Politics of Sectarianism in the Middle East, May 11, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Sepaker: Toby Matthiesen
    - Women in Computing in the Arab World, May 17-18, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiator/Speaker: Sana Odeh
    - Rethinking Historical Space, May 19-21, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Martin Klimke, David Ludden, Lauren Minsky, Mark Swislocki
    - The Spaces and Places of History, May 19, 2015 (Box E-records)
      Program Officiators/Speakers: Prasenjit Duara, Richard Eaton, Barbara Weinstein